Hello, English learners and welcome
to English pod. My name is Marco.
I'm Amira.
Amira and I are here today with an
interesting lesson about a hotel situation.
Amira, why don't you give us
a little bit more information?
Well, the situation is
taking place in a hotel and
someone is checking in
and is obtaining an upgrade.
Okay, that's an interesting
word. Why don't we listen to the
dialogue and then we'll come
back and explain all this vocabulary.
Good afternoon. What can I do for you?
I'd like to check in please. I have a
reservation under the name Anthony Roberts.
Alright, Robert. Oh,
Mr. Roberts, we've been expecting
you and here is your keycard
to the presidential suite.
But there must be some mistake.
My reservation was for a standard room.
Are you sure? Let me double check.
Yeah, here. This is my confirmation number.
You're right, Mr. Roberts.
There seems to be a mix-up.
Unfortunately, we're
overbooked at the moment.
So... Not to worry. We're pleased to
offer you a complimentary upgrade.
Woo-hoo, presidential suite, baby.
Okay, everyone. That is nice, huh?
Yeah, the guy is really excited that
he's going to get the presidential suite.
Yes, there's some interesting
phrases and vocabulary items here.
And I know, Marco, you want
to talk about some of them.
Right. The first one,
and this is really useful
for all of our listeners
who travel a lot.
This phrase will come in handy. And it
is, I have a reservation under the name.
Under the name. Under the name.
So, before we explain
this phrase, let's listen to
some examples on how it
is used in other situations,
and then we'll come back
and give you more information.
My secretary made a
reservation under my name.
I'm sorry, sir.
I don't have a reservation under that name.
Do you have a reservation
under the name Smith?
All right, some really
good examples there on
how we could use this
phrase in other situations.
But just in case, let
me explain it real fast.
Under the name means
that when you go to the
restaurant or a hotel and
you tell them your name,
they know that you
are the person that they
have been expecting.
They have been waiting.
Yes. Well, I have chosen another
useful phrase for you, and it is mix up.
Mix up. Mix up. There seems to be a mix up.
Before we talk about this phrase, let's
listen to some examples of how it is used.
There was a mix up at the airport,
and my bags were sent to Antarctica.
I'm sorry, sir. There's been a terrible
mix up with giving you the wrong baby.
Okay, that was useful and funny.
Yeah, that's the baby situation.
Oh my God, imagine that happening.
Yeah, I know.
Well, guys, so a mix up is a
confusion or a misunderstanding.
Mm-hmm, exactly. Well put.
All right, Marco, what do you have for us?
Okay, the next word that should
take a look at is overbooked.
Overbooked. Overbooked.
Overbooked. What does that mean?
So if a hotel or a flight is
overbooked, it means that they are full.
They are more than full. Right, so
they cannot accept any more people.
Exactly.
Okay, now why is this phrase useful?
Because it happens all the time.
There's so many other
situations where you can use this
word or hear it from other
native English speakers.
For example, a bus or a
train can be overbooked.
Exactly, that's really common.
Okay, let's take a
look at the last phrase
for today and that is
complimentary upgrade.
Complimentary upgrade.
So this means that, for
example, when the hotel is
overbooked and all of
their standard rooms are full,
they will give you a better room,
a more expensive room, but free.
Yes, because it was not your fault.
Right, this also happens sometimes
if you're lucky on airplane flights.
Yes.
So if you are an economy class and an
airplane, but for some reason it's overbooked,
they will move you to business
class or first class for free.
I have a similar story, but I'm
not going to tell you about it now.
For now, let's go and listen
to the dialogue one more time
and when we come
back, we'll talk some more.
Good afternoon.
What can I do for you?
I'd like to check in, please.
I have a reservation under
the name Anthony Roberts.
All right.
Robert.
Oh, Mr. Roberts.
We've been expecting you and here
is your keycard to the presidential suite.
But there must be some mistake.
My reservation was for a standard room.
Are you sure?
Let me double check.
Yeah.
Here.
This is my confirmation number.
You're right, Mr. Roberts.
There seems to be a mix up.
Unfortunately, we're
overbooked at the moment.
So not to worry, we're pleased to
offer you a complimentary upgrade.
Whoa, presidential suite, baby.
I love listening to the dialogue.
It's just so nice to see that someone
is enjoying his upgrade so much.
Yeah, especially since he was
expecting just a really normal room
and now he's going
to be treated like a king.
So Marco, have you ever
gotten a complimentary upgrade?
Yes.
Yes, I did.
When I was traveling through India,
I bought a normal seat in the train.
But for some reason, it was overbooked.
So I talked to the station manager and I
got a complimentary upgrade to first class.
I had a similar experience as well.
I was flying from Shanghai to Qatar
and I actually had an economy seat.
But for some reason, they just
upgraded me and I was so happy.
Oh, really?
Like, it wasn't overbooked.
Well, I'm not sure because
normally the night flight
is not that full, but they
upgraded me for some reason.
And I was so happy.
It was an upgrade to first class.
Wow, that's really cool.
I would prefer a first class upgrade
on an airplane, yeah, any day.
Well, you know what?
It really amazed me was
like the food you get there.
You know, you have a five course meal.
Oh, really?
Yes.
And you get all the
drinks you can get, right?
Exactly.
Wow.
That would be really happy there.
All right, everyone.
We're at a time today, but
be sure to listen tomorrow
because we'll be back again
with another great podcast.
And also, don't forget to go
to our website at EnglishPod.
com and leave us all your questions
and comments in our community forum.
Yes.
And we would also
appreciate your suggestions.
And I hope you enjoyed the lesson today.
And Marko and I will be back tomorrow
was another great lesson for you.
But for now, it's bye.